Welcome back.
This chapter is probably one of the most important because we dive into the Lorawan protocol.
There will be different parts in this chapter, and the first one will be about the overall Lorawan ecosystem.
.
This includes the Lorawan version specification provided by the Lorawan Alliance.
And in that part, we take the opportunity to explain the differences between the Lora modulation and
the Lorawan protocol.
Obviously will also see the three main parts of the Lorawan
infrastructure, which are the end devices, the gateways and the Lorawan server.
The Lorawan infrastructure is a secure network and as every secure networks, it needs confidentiality, authentication
and data integrity.
and we will therefore explain what solutions have been implemented to make it work.
On the device size we will see the different classes name A, B or C with these end device will do some tests to highlight
their capabilities.
The second part is about the two different methods to activate an end device on the network server.
There are two types called ABP or OTAA.
When we begin with Lorawan network, it's quite difficult to understand what are they for.
That's why in the third part will present a series of "how to" to present demand situation you will have
to deal with when implementing a Lorawan infrastructure, how to prevent replay attack, then second
how to change the communication parameters, and third, how to change network operators.
And we will see that depending on your activation method, the answer of this question would be different.
Finally, you remember that Lora transmission parameters like the spreading factor or the power transmission
have a huge influence on the end device consumption.
But it's not that easy to find a trade off between the power consumption, the range and the bitrate.
So how can we do it now?
I want provide a solution called ADR for adaptive data rate.
ADR is an automatic way to optimize end device autonomy while being sure that it can always reach the
network.
So that's a very challenging agenda, but I'm sure we can do it together.
Let's get to work.